[music]
>> Uh, the message that I have for us this
morning
is in the form of a question.
And I want I want each one of us to ask
ourselves this question and think about
it very seriously. And the question is,
do you know Jesus? Or apply it more
personally,
do I know Jesus?
If I stood at the entrance and asked you
that question as you walked in,
I'm sure I'd get very different
responses. Some of you would immediately
answer, "Yes, I know Jesus." You'll be
able to tell me when you met Jesus, what
message was preached, what day and time
that was.
Others of you might be a little bit
offended by the question. "Uh, of course
I know Jesus. That's why I'm here.
That's why I came to church this
morning. I have served Jesus. I've known
Jesus for a very long time. I met Jesus
when I was uh uh in Sunday school. I
walked with him through CU and now I'm
all uh still serving him in church."
So, for you to be asked whether you know
Jesus might not be the best thing to
hear. Thank you.
But I want us to
take I want to take a journey with you
uh through the centuries down to the
first century and we walk into a house.
We find a man who is in chains. Uh,
unbeknownst to us, this man is the
Apostle Paul.
And we approach him and ask him,
"Do you know Jesus?"
After a long pause,
we get this answer, which is our text
that was just read to us very
beautifully. I want to read it again.
Philippians 3, beginning with verse 10.
Here's what Paul says.
I want to know Christ and the power of
his resurrection
and the fellowship of sharing in his
sufferings, becoming like him in his
death, and so somehow to attain to the
resurrection from the dead.
Now, that arrests our attention because
this is the Apostle Paul, and he says
that he wants to know Jesus.
What in the world does he mean by that?
Doesn't Paul already know Jesus?
In Acts chapter 9, uh that Paul was on
his way to Damascus to to persecute
Christians, and he was knocked down, as
you remember the story, and blinded by a
bright light.
Then he had a voice, very clear voice
from heaven saying to him, "Saul, Saul,
why do you persecute me?" And then he
asked the question, "Who are you, Lord?"
And the voice said, "I am Jesus, whom
you are persecuting."
Jesus literally introduced himself to
Paul.
And Paul says he wants to know Jesus.
Didn't Paul already know Jesus?
At the time Paul was writing this letter
to the Philippians,
scholars tell us that he was near the
end of his life. He had lived a life of
full service to God, of relentless
service to God, and commitment to
Christ. He was in prison because of
preaching Christ, because of faith in
Christ. He wrote
the about 13 of the books of the New
Testament.
He wrote the Bible. He wrote the
inspired word of God. And yet he says he
wants to know Christ. Paul performed
miracles. He even raised the dead. Paul
suffered more than anyone I know
that I've read of in his missionary
journeys trying to establish churches
and lead multitudes to Christ. How can
he say that he wants to know Christ?
Paul, the Paul who was taken up to to
the third heaven and shown things that
he wasn't allowed to even speak about.
How can a man like that say that he
wants to know Jesus? And what do we
mean? What do you and I mean when we say
that we want to know Jesus? You know, we
take we we speak about those things very
very casually. Remember when I was a
kid, uh the song that would teach us
in Sunday school. I don't know if they
taught those those uh kind of songs in
uh in Nairobi, but in the place where I
was, they were teaching us to sing, "Nam
skia kichwa tumbo na mgongo." Was that
the only one?
Good. I hear others singing this
evening. What do we mean by that? Cuz I
can tell you I did not feel Jesus in my
stomach or in my knees at that time. But
I did not want to look like the only
heretic in the group, so I sang along.
But what does that mean? What do we mean
when we say we know Jesus? And what does
Paul mean
when he says that he wants to know Jesus
after all that he had done? What does he
mean by that? Paul packs a lot of
information in these two verses, and
it's not possible for me to be able to
uh to unpack everything that he puts in
here. So, I'm just going to do the
highlights of what he's talking about in
the hope that we will have a better
clearer picture of what he's talking
about here, and that we'll become a
little bit more focused in our pursuit
of who God is. So, I'm going to give you
five things that Paul says in these
in these uh two short verses here. And
the first point is this. This is what
Paul means when he says he wants to know
Jesus. He means that he wants you and me
to know that Jesus is the goal of our
salvation. Point number one, Jesus is
the goal of our salvation. He is the
ultimate prize. If you get everything
else and not get Jesus,
you have missed the mark. You have lost.
You have not finished the race because
Jesus is the goal of our salvation.
The goal or the destiny of our salvation
is God himself. So, if you run and you
don't touch the string,
you have not finished the race properly.
And touching the string in this case
means knowing God, getting in touch with
God himself. That's what Paul wants us
to be able to know about. I remember
many years ago,
as I was
in my first year of seminary out in
California, I had a neighbor who was a
very educated man. He had three PhDs to
his name and he was deeply into the New
Age movement. I would go to his house
and he would be in a room meditating
with candles all around him and he
looked like he was in a trance. He
didn't even know you were there if you
found him in that state. And I remember
sharing the gospel very clearly with him
and he listened carefully as I explained
who Jesus was and Jesus died
on his behalf. And he said the words
that I will never forget. He looked at
me and he said to me,
"Hearing you talk about God is like
listening to an atheist."
I knew enough to know that was not a
compliment. So, I said to him,
"I'm confused. I don't know what you
mean by that." I said, "I just told you
that the God who created you wants to
have a relationship with you and you're
telling me that I am an atheist, that I
don't believe God exists." He said,
"This is the reason I said that.
All you Christians have are statements
and creeds and you think that if people
accept those statements and those
creeds, if they accept them, they say
yes to them, uh they are their journey
with God is over, that they have the
problem uh of God has been solved in
their lives. When I pray, I get in touch
with powers that you know nothing
about." Now, as I like I said, I was
just beginning my studies in um
in seminary, and that set me to this
journey of wanting to know what it
really means to know God. Is it just a
collection of doctrines? Just statements
that we get people to to accept to say,
"Yes, I believe that." And that's the
end of it. Paul is saying that is not
what it means to be a follower of Jesus
Christ, because the end goal of our
salvation is truly knowing God. It's
knowing God. Jesus is the price. Jesus
is the is what we are expected to find
at the end. He is our destiny. Our
destiny in our pursuit of uh
of every Christian is God himself. This
is true even in the Old Testament.
That's how how how how God has revealed
himself right from the very beginning.
For those of us who've been clamoring so
much to get to Canaan, I keep hearing
that language over and over again. Here,
we need to understand that the
destination was not Canaan. The
destination is actually God himself. In
Exodus chapter 19 and verse 4,
this is what we read. This is God
speaking to the Israelites. Exodus 19
and verse 4, "You yourselves have seen
what I did to Egypt and how I lifted you
on eagle's wings and brought you to
myself."
The whole journey was meant to bring the
Israelites to God himself. In Exodus
chapter 33,
which is one of my favorite passages of
scripture, God makes an incredible offer
to the Israelites. He says to them, "I
will send an angel before you. The angel
will fight the battles for you, and the
land will still be flowing with milk and
honey, but I will not go with you
because you are stiff-necked people, and
I might destroy you along the way." Can
you imagine what prosperity preachers
would do with that? That God is still
going to give you the land flowing with
milk and honey. You have all his
blessings. You have angels fighting for
you and God is in there to tell you what
to do.
That would be a welcome thing for those
who are only looking for God for for
God's blessings and not for God himself.
But what did Moses say in chapter in
verse 15? He said, "If your presence
doesn't go with us, do not send us from
here." Because he understood that Canaan
wasn't the just the place. Canaan was
God himself. Being able to meet up with
God. And Paul says here, "I want to know
Christ." And I hope that's the cry of
your heart as well that you want to know
Christ. That you haven't arrived. You
don't feel like you have arrived. That
you have
done everything you needed to do. You
have no more growth to do because you
and God are like that. You're best
buddies.
Let me tell you, knowing God is a much
much deeper thing. And that's what Paul
is talking about here. Now that I'm many
good things in our lives, they can
actually take the place of knowing God
in in in us. For example,
for some of us, it could be the
scriptures. And we feel as long as I put
in my 15-20 minutes per day and all of
that, I am fine. I have known God. But
Jesus, speaking to the Pharisees, says
this to them in John chapter 5 and verse
39, "You study the scriptures diligently
because you think that in them you have
eternal life. These are the very
scriptures that testify about me. Yet
you refuse to come to me to have life."
That even the word of God is a means to
an end. And the end is knowing God.
That's what God want us to be able to
do. Even the scriptures cannot take that
place. They are a means to an end. And
you can search the scriptures. These
people knew the the the Bible backwards
and forwards. And yet when God stood
before them, they could not recognize
him.
Something else really good that can take
the place of of knowing God is our
pursuit of eternal life. And I hear
people sharing their testimonies and
they always talk about doing this and
that and all of that so that they can
they will inherit eternal life someday.
That is still a confusion about what God
is really offering us because if you ask
the average person what today Christian
today what eternal life is, they will
tell you that eternal life is getting to
live with God when you die.
But that is not what eternal life is
according to the scriptures. Of course,
we will get to live with God when we
die, but that's not what eternal life is
in the scriptures. The Bible comes very
close to giving us a definition of
eternal life in John chapter 17 and
verse 3.
John 17:3 and it says this, "And this is
eternal life, that they may know you,
the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom
you have sent." Eternal life in know is
knowing God through Jesus and it begins
the moment you and I become believers.
That is the goal of our salvation. It is
to know God and that's why Paul says
that he wants to know God. There are
other things that can take the place of
our pursuit of God. It could be our
identity markers,
our identity markers or it could be um
our accomplishments or what we own,
those kinds of things. They can become
our real pursuit in lives and if they
were removed, our lives would fall
apart. And Paul says, "You can remove
all those things from me." He was
writing this when he was in chains. And
what he says in in this passage is an
amazing thing that his desire is to know
God. That's all he is living for. He
begins this chapter by warning the
Philippians that there will be there
will come people who would teach them a
different doctrine, a different message,
try to put something else in the place
of their pursuit of God. And Paul uses
some very harsh words in this letter. He
says he calls them dogs in in verse two,
evildoers, and mutilators of the flesh.
Because he realizes that if this
Philippians follow that, if they accept
that that they are going to be in
trouble because they will have lost
their way. They will have missed the
path which is to know God himself.
This book of Philippians, I wish we had
the time to look at it in more detail
because it has so much teachers that all
the things that we spend most of our
time pursuing, we get to the point where
those things begin to mean nothing to
us. I remember speaking just about a
month ago to a man who was very very
ill.
And he had come over to our house and I
was I was talking to him and he said to
me, "I know I'm not going to be here for
a long time. And it's amazing because I
really don't miss anything in this world
right now except my family. It's only my
family that I care for right now and and
friend the friends that I have and I
hope they they'll be okay." It's It's
amazing because this is a
a man who had a lot of things that he
could he could be thinking of and
talking about, but he got to the point
where what really mattered is all that
stood in front of him. Paul has all
these accolades, all these
accomplishments that he lists for us in
verse four.
If someone else thinks that they have
reason to put confidence in the flesh, I
have more. Circumcised on the eighth
day, of the people of Israel. This is a
true Israelite. He was circumcised on
the eighth day, of the tribe of
Benjamin. He is from the royal tribe.
The first king of Israel came from the
tribe of Benjamin, King Saul. And it's
possible that Paul himself
was named after after after King Saul.
So, he's proud of of of that heritage.
And he's a Hebrew of Hebrews. He lived
in a Greek city in Tarsus, and yet he
learned Hebrew, and he was actually
trained under the best Hebrew teacher of
the time, Gamaliel. And so, he's a
Hebrew of Hebrews. And he, in regard to
the law, he's a Pharisee. You could not
rise up higher than that in Israel when
it came to the law, to obeying to
obeying the law of God.
Um
And as for zeal, persecuting the church.
As for righteousness based on the law,
faultless. This is the Apostle Paul. He
had all these accolades. He has an
impeccable CV. He has accomplished
everything that you could accomplish in
that day to get all the respect that you
deserved, which is uh which is true of
many of us in this in this in this
building today.
But in verse 9,
Paul does something amazing. He says,
"Take all those things and put them
together in a pile." All those
accomplishments, every one of them.
And then compare those things with the
surpassing greatness of knowing our Lord
and Savior Jesus Christ. You know what
he Paul says? He says, "All those things
uh my translation says garbage." But the
word he uses, the Greek word skubalon,
doesn't doesn't just mean garbage. It
actually means feces, excrement. He
doesn't use It's not translated that
way, but that's what that's what Paul is
saying, that they are nothing compared
to knowing Christ. See, some
And when we when when we when we reflect
on our lives, when we look at the things
that we pursue in life, many times it is
those things that we value the most that
sometimes keep us from knowing who God
really is. And Paul wants to change that
in your life. He wants to change that in
my life. Another thing that could keep
us from from from knowing God is our
self-righteousness. He says that in
verse 9. He says this, "I do not want to
be found with a type of righteousness
that comes from keeping the law. Just
patting myself on the back because of
how good I am, the things that I have
done. Paul says, that won't work. That
will not get me where I want to go. I
want to be clothed in God's
righteousness. Righteousness that comes
from God and that is received by faith.
That is the only way that we can be able
to stand faultless before the throne of
God. Jesus came to save us, not just
from the bad things we have done,
but also from the good things that we do
that we think can make us righteous.
He came to save us, not just from the
bad things we have done, but also from
the good things that we do thinking that
those those things will make us
acceptable before God. Some people know
that they need forgiveness for their
sins. Far fewer people realize that they
need forgiveness for their
self-righteousness.
The prostitute knows that she needs
mercy, but the Pharisee thinks that he
deserves heaven. One of them is closer
to God to the kingdom of God than the
other. Remember the two sons, the the
prodigal sons, both of them. One was
lost in the wilderness. It's very easy
for us to see his mistakes, his evils
and and and very easy for us to expect
repentance from him. But the older
brother who was lost at home, that's a
very difficult thing for us to be able
to see that he really truly is lost
because he says that he has lived for
his father all this time. And we may be
feeling the same way. We have things
that we can look at, the things that we
have we have done, how we have helped
others, how we have prayed, how we read
the scriptures, how we have read Bible
study and all these kind of things, and
that can keep us from knowing God. So,
let me ask you this question.
Do you know Jesus? And now the question
sounds different in when we reflect on
what Paul is doing here, and we are not
so sure anymore. Because like Paul, we
need to get to the point where we can
begin to say, yes, I really do want to
know Jesus.
The answer again is not as simple, but
Paul is guiding us in the way that we
should go. Point number one,
Christ is the goal, or Jesus is the goal
of our salvation. The next thing that
Paul says is that he wants to know the
power of Christ's resurrection, which
brings us to the second point. Now,
power is something that all Kenyans know
something about because we've already
been told
But what kind of power is Paul talking
about? He says this, point number two,
Jesus is the source of our strength.
He is the source of our strength. Paul
understood that the Christian life is
not difficult. It's actually impossible
to live it without God. It's not
difficult, it's impossible to live it
out without God. And that's that's why
he says
he wants to know the power of the of
Christ's resurrection. Now,
when he says that, he isn't thinking
about having power to perform miracles.
He's already done all kinds of miracles
including raising the dead. That's not
what he's talking about. What he is
talking about is allowing the power of
God to work to so work in his life that
he begins to become like who Jesus truly
is. He begins to be to be changed to
become what God meant meant for him to
be right from the very beginning. In
Ephesians 1 and verse 19, he's he's he
tells the Ephesians that he wants them
to know the power that rolled the stone
away and got Jesus out of the tomb. He
wants them to know that power. And in
Philippians 2 and verse 13, he says, "It
is God who works in you to will and to
act in in order to fulfill his good
purpose in you." That's the power he's
looking for. God's power working in your
life to change you so you can become the
kind of a person that he created you to
be. That's the power that he's looking
for in his life. Paul wants God's power
to work in him
to change him in conformity to what he
tells us in Romans chapter 8 and verse
29 where it says that God's ultimate
purpose for his for his children is that
they can become conformed to the image
of his son.
You know something
um
else
um maybe maybe this this this this um
bears repeating but I won't I'll I'll
skip it. Let's Let's just go to the next
point. Point number one was Jesus is the
goal of our salvation. Point number two,
Jesus is the source of our strength. The
Christian life is unlivable. It's
impossible without the power of God
because what we think is righteousness
Jesus count or God counts as filthy
rags. Only what we do what God does
through us to reach other people. That's
what counts. So he wants that life to be
able to be at work in him. Jesus is the
source of our strength. Point number
three,
Jesus is our companion
in suffering. Jesus is our companion in
suffering. Paul wants to know the
fellowship of sharing in Christ's
sufferings. The fellowship of sharing in
Christ's sufferings. That's an
incredible thing that he says there
because if you understand what this word
meant, fellowship, it's a Greek word
koinonia. He uses this word in uh six
different ways uh in this in this
letter.
If you understand what it means, you'll
see how profound this idea really is
because we use fellowship very loosely
these days. That you meet somebody for
coffee at Java House and you say you had
very very good fellowship with that
person. That's not the way they used it.
Uh in when Paul was writing this, um the
word fellowship meant
that you are so united in purpose and
love with someone else that when that
person suffers, you also suffer.
That, um,
if you and I have koinonia, your
purposes are so tied up with mine that
if your purposes are not not going well,
if life is not going well, mine is not
going well, either. It was actually used
to describe Siamese twins, twins who are
who are born conjoined joined together.
This word was used to describe them that
they were actually in fellowship. Now,
fellowship cannot get any tighter than
that. It was used of business partners.
When you invest your money and you want
your business to grow, if one person
pulls out, the whole thing collapses. It
affects both of you. That's how it was
That's how strong this, uh, this
fellowship was. And this church, this
Philippian church, is a dream church for
any pastor because for some reason, they
got the word of God so easily and so
carefully that they actually,
uh, bonded with Paul so well that every
place Paul went, they sent people to go
and help him. They sent him money. They
were helping They And he says in chapter
four, you you can look at that later. He
says, "No other church did that, but
this Philippian church was in
fellowship." And Paul tells them, "The
God who began that good work in you will
carry it on to completion because of the
powerful fellowship that he had with
people." But here,
he is talking about the fellowship that
we can have with Jesus Christ even in
his sufferings. He is our companion even
in the midst of sufferings. By the way,
as, uh, as a person who likes us to talk
to people who are not Christians and who
I spend most of my time doing that, I
have to step back and ask myself, "How
do these other religions or these other
ways of thinking about the world, how do
they explain suffering and pain and evil
and all of that?" And there are actually
two other explanations that we get other
than the biblical one. And one is the
Eastern way of thinking where you have
Hinduism and Buddhism and Shintoism and
those those are those religions. And
what they tell you, some of them will
tell you that evil, pain, and suffering
is actually maya, that is actually an
illusion. It's really not there. That's
how they explain it. It's It's an
illusion. Others will tell you your main
problem, that's what the Buddhist will
tell you, your main problem is that you
allow desire to control your life. You
should get rid of all desires. And if
you do that, of course you're not going
to desire to do well, and so you're not
going to suffer anymore. The problem is
how do you get rid of the desire to want
to get rid of the desire?
That doesn't work.
You know, there's I remember reading a a
poem. I don't I don't read poems that
much, but this is a very short one, and
so I read it and I was thinking of it
because everybody says this is one of
the best poems ever written by a man
called Kobayashi Issa, who died in 1828.
One of the four greatest masters of
Japanese haiku of poems. He was a
Buddhist, and so he would tell you to
get rid of desire. Unfortunately,
Issa's life was marked by hardship. His
mother died when he was very young, and
his stepmother was mistreated him quite
a bit. He himself lost a number of
of kids in infancy, and also his he
married his wife first wife died, his
second wife died. He he suffered a lot,
lived in poverty, and a lot of a lot of
suffering. But here is the poem he
wrote. Remember his philosophy is you're
supposed to get rid of desire so that
you you're going to solve all your
problems of pain. But here is his poem.
This world of dew, d e w, this world of
dew is a world of dew. And yet, and yet.
In that
short poem, he packs a lot because what
he's saying is this, "I know that life
is temporary and fragile, like dew. It's
here and it's gone. I know this, and yet
knowing that doesn't make my loss any
easier to bear." In other words, he is
trying to fit suffering and pain in his
philosophy, and he finds out that
actually pain and suffering push through
that philosophy, and he finds himself
wishing there was more.
That is from the Eastern perspective.
What about naturalism? Atheism, which is
the foundation of our educational
systems the world over today.
What do they have to say about
suffering? Here's Richard Dawkins, the
best known atheist of our day. He writes
this, "In a universe of blind physical
forces and genetic replication, some
people are going to get hurt, other
people are going to get lucky, and you
won't find any rhyme or reason in it,
nor any justice. The universe that we
observe has precisely the properties we
should expect if there is a bottom, no
design, no purpose, no evil, no good,
nothing, but pitiless indifference. DNA
neither cares nor knows nor cares.
DNA just is, and we dance to its music."
That's what he says, "Things just are."
There's no point complaining about
suffering, because things just happen.
That's the answer he gives. The Bible
gives a very different answer. It
presents us with a God who enters our
suffering, who understands what you're
going through, who understands what I'm
going through, and can actually be be
able to come before him and acknowledge,
"This is a problem. I don't have to hide
it or to pretend it's not there. It's
not a delusion. It's not an illusion.
It's actually there, and I can actually
present this evil, pain, and suffering
before a God who I know understands me
and cares about what I'm going through."
Edward Shillito wrote this poem after
World War I, the First World War. He
says this, "The other gods were strong."
So, he's looking at the gods offered by
men. And the gods offered by men, we
imagine a god who is so powerful and who
is so different from us that he he can
really we can expect that kind of a god
to relate to anything that we are going
through. When we craft gods ourselves,
that's what gods that our gods look
like. But when God reveals himself, he
comes to us as a god who actually
suffers and is able to enter into our
situation, understand what we're going
through. So he he he writes, "The other
gods were strong, but thou was weak.
They roared, but thou didst stumble to
your throne. But to our wounds only
gods' wounds can speak, and not a god
has wounds but thou alone alone. Not a
god has wounds but thou alone."
Some of you walked in here today
carrying a burden that nobody else knows
about.
You smile when people say hello to you.
You sing the songs when we sing and even
dance a little bit, but your heart is
breaking. And Paul's point is this,
the Christ the Christians may not escape
suffering, but no Christian has to go
that pain and suffering alone because
Jesus is with us and he's gone through
it. And he is there to comfort you. And
he is there to meet with you.
Our God has wounds.
That is our savior Jesus Christ. Point
number one,
Jesus is the goal of our salvation.
Point number two, Jesus is the source of
our strength. And point number three,
Jesus is our companion in suffering. And
point number four,
Jesus is our example in death. To be
conformed to him in his death. He is our
example in death. This is a topic we
don't like to talk about until we are
forced to talk about it. When we lose a
loved one or somebody that that we care
about, we are forced to think about it.
And it's a very very painful topic and I
wish we could talk about it more before
we get here because throughout history
Christians have been known as people who
actually know how to suffer and die
well. Remember reading a
story about this
theologian called William Lane who took
it upon himself to disciple a musician
called Michael Card and and they spent a
lot of time together. He discipled him,
he mentored him in his theology and all
of that and then
William Lane was diagnosed with that
with cancer and was going to be dying
and so he moved closer to where Michael
Card lived and Michael Card asked him
why he would want to do that. You know
what he said?
I want to teach you how a Christian man
dies.
How a Christian woman dies. Paul
has come to terms with this issue and we
all must come to terms with it because
we are all perishable. We are here for a
short time. We are perishable from a
physical perspective but we don't have
to perish ever and ever as we will see
in a second. Paul talks about this
when the focus of your life is to know
Christ, when your life is fueled by the
power that raised Jesus from the dead,
when you know that you will never suffer
alone, that God is with you even in
pain, it becomes easier to surrender to
him and to honor him even in death. This
is not the first time that Paul is
talking about death in this book. In
chapter 1 he talks about his struggle
whether he should remain or whether he
should go and he says for me to go is
actually better. I would rather be with
Jesus right now but for your sake I I
know I will remain. He says that. So
he's he's torn between the two and he
actually prefers to be with Jesus. In
chapter 2
verse 17 he says that he's being poured
out like a drink offering. And then in
you know he uses those same words in the
in the book of 2 Timothy and here he
talks about becoming like Christ in his
death. He is talking about the God's
power working in him so much that the
life that he's going to be living is
going to be a life that will prepare him
for that moment of death when that
moment comes. He'll be prepared when
that moment comes because of what the
power of God will have done in his life.
This is dying well, and Paul is talking
about that here. I know some of you and
in a with so many people here,
maybe you just buried a loved one. Maybe
you have somebody struggling with this
kind of uh issue uh in in the hospital
or or something like that.
It's so helpful to know
that even in death, we can honor and
glorify God because Jesus has gone
through it and we can and he is with us
in it that we do not suffer alone. Um
if
What do you do with some somebody like
that? Somebody like Paul who is thinking
this way, who lives this way. What do
you do to him? If you tell him that
you're going to put him to death, what
is he going to say? That's great. I'll
just you just sending me to my master
earlier. If you tell him, I'll make you
suffer, what does he say? It doesn't
matter because if I suffer, I'm I'm just
being identified with my savior Jesus
Christ. And if you leave him alone, he
will continue to preach the gospel.
There's really nothing you can do with a
person like Paul. And God wants us to be
able to get to the point where nobody
can do anything to us. We are we don't
fear people who can kill the body, but
they can't do anything about our soul.
The only person to fear is God, and it's
that God who welcomes us to himself.
I don't know how many of you have seen
uh
uh some interviews that are going around
by a man named Ben Sasse, who was a who
was a former US senator and president of
the University of Florida. He was
diagnosed with several different kinds
of cancers, and the cancer has ravaged
his body. You can actually see it uh in
his face during the interviews, and it's
I I was watching one of these
interviews, and the interviewer asked
him,
"Are you angry
at God?" And his answer really surprised
me. He says, "No, not at all. I'm not
angry at God." He says he doesn't expect
a sovereign God to say yes to every
prayer that he prays. Ben doesn't want a
God who's like He says, "Because I can't
see what God can see. I want God to give
me what's best, and if his best is for
this cancer to take me to him, that's
fine." He says, "I
I don't I He says cancer doesn't play
any role in my salvation.
It's not helping me in my salvation at
all, but it has a sanctifying effect
because it's revealing to me, uh to Ben,
what matters the most in life." And then
he says things, "Things are not right in
my soul. My soul thinks Ben should be
God, and I want that to die. Cancer
sucks, but I'm pretty grateful that
cancer is a stake against my delusional
self-idolatry."
What is he saying? That cancer has
actually is like a like like a sword
that has pierced his self-idolatry, his
pride, and now he's able to surrender
himself to God. Those are incredible
words to hear. Set aside the politics,
just a person who is now truly focused
on Christ being able to present himself
that way. That was That's what
Christians have always been known for,
being able to die well. I know this is
not a topic that we like to talk about,
but it's a topic that Paul is talking
about, and it's one that we need to be
able to properly
reflect on. Jesus is the goal of our
salvation. God saved us to bring us to
himself.
Jesus is the source of our strength. The
Christian life is unlivable without the
power that comes from God, and Jesus is
our companion in suffering. We do not
suffer alone. We suffer with him. And
Jesus is our example in death. And point
number five,
Jesus
is our eternal future.
Jesus is our eternal future.
You know something
powerful that I see in the scriptures,
some verses you read the verse and you
feel like um
um the author or the speaker doesn't
really know what he or she is talking
about, mostly he's talking about. This
is Jesus himself speaking
in John chapter 5 and verse 24.
Very truly I tell you, whoever hears my
word and believes him who sent me has
eternal life and will not be judged but
has crossed over from
death to life.
And actually some translation says will
not die, that we don't actually die. Uh
how can that be the case? The reason is
because we have crossed over from death
to life. Um
Bible teachers have said throughout
history
one of the Bible city teachers
that when you die, it will take a while
before you actually know that you're
dead. Things will look different and you
will not
you and then after all you thought, "Oh,
so this is what happened. I'm dead." But
you're still there because you crossed
over from death to life. If you are in
Christ, you don't actually die. You just
move from this dimension to next
dimension and life continues for you.
This is how you see as we presented in
The Chronicles of Narnia.
Uh those are really good books to read
to the to your kids. I read them to my
kids when they were younger. And the
last one, if you've not read them, I'm
sorry, I'm going to to um ruin it for
you, the plot for you. In The Last
Battle, there's a train accident and the
the actors in that book, the the
Pevensie children, uh they are in the
accident but they they get out of the
accident and Aslan, who's a figure of
Christ, the lion comes to talk to is
talking to them and he has to explain to
them what happened because they have no
idea what happened because nothing looks
different to them. Because they're in
Narnia, nothing looks different to them.
And Aslan says, uh he looks at them and
says,
"There was a real accident. You are
dead.
The time is The time is over. The
holidays have begun. The dream is ended.
This is the morning.
It's just the beginning of your new life
in heaven. And C.S. Lewis concludes,
"All their life in this world and all
their adventures in Narnia had only been
the cover on the title page. And now
they were beginning chapter one of the
great story."
That's our portion in Christ. That
nothing really can touch who we are as
followers of Christ. That's what Paul
was talking about in these powerful
verses that he gives to us in this book
of Philippians. I want to close um
with this quote by a man called Malcolm
Muggeridge. He was a brilliant um
journalist, probably the greatest
journalist of the last century. And he
became a follower of Christ late in his
life after covering the the life of
Mother Teresa. Here's what Malcolm
Muggeridge wrote.
"I may I suppose regard myself a
relatively successful man. People
occasionally stare at me in the streets.
That's fame. I can fairly easily earn
enough to qualify for admission to the
highest levels of the internal revenue.
That's success. Furnished with money and
a little fame, even the elderly, if they
if they care to, may partake of trendy
diversions. That's pleasure. It may
happen once in a while that something I
said or wrote was sufficiently heeded
for me to persuade myself that it
presented serious impact on our time.
That's fulfillment. Yet I say to you,
and I beg you to believe me, multiply
these tiny triumphs by a million, add
them all together, and they are nothing,
less than nothing, a positive impediment
measured against one drop of that living
water Christ offers to the spiritually
thirsty, irrespective of who or what
they are."
Paul knew Jesus on the Damascus Road.
Paul preached Jesus throughout the Roman
Empire. He suffered for Jesus. He wrote
much of the New Testament. Yet at the
end of his life he says, "I want to know
Jesus." Jesus is the goal of our
salvation. He is the source of our
strength. He's our companion in
suffering. He's our example in death and
he is our eternal future. The question
is not merely, "Do you know Jesus?"
Matthew 7 from verse 21 to verse 23 says
this,
"Not everyone who says to me, 'Lord,
Lord,' will enter the kingdom of heaven,
but only the one who does the will of my
father who is in heaven. Many will say
to me on that day, 'Lord, Lord, did we
not prophesy in your name and in your
name drive out demons and in your name
perform many miracles?' Then I'll tell
them plainly, 'I never knew you. Away
from me, you evildoers.'"
The question is not merely, "Do you know
Jesus?" The question actually is, "Does
Jesus know you?"
God bless you.